FENIL R. DOSHI

RESEARCH INTERESTS

In my research, I am exploring the nature of visual representations underlying mid-level vision by trying to characterize the tuning and spatial topographies of proto-object representations, and the kinds of mechanisms that can operate over it. To this end, I combine computational models of vision, behavioral psychophysics, and neuroimaging data to gain deeper insights into the emergent neural and behavioral signatures of a hierarchical visual processor.

EDUCATION

Harvard University, Cambridge, MA

2021 - Present

Ph.D. Program in Psychology (Cognition, Brain, and Behavior)

Advisor: Dr. George Alvarez and Dr. Talia Konkle

SRM Institute of Science and Technology, Chennai, India

2014 - 2018

B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering (GPA: 8.65/10.0)

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Harvard University, Dept. of Psychology

Nov 2018 - Dec 2020

Research Assistant (Fellow), Vision Sciences Lab

Faculty Advisor: Dr. George Alvarez

<u>Focus</u>: Worked on models and behavioral psychophysics experiments that account for human judgements in intuitive physics tasks and capacity-limits in human visual working memory.

Harvard Medical School (BWH)

Jan 2018 - July 2018

Research Intern, Shafiee Lab

Faculty Advisor: Dr. Hadi Shafiee

Focus:

Trained convolutional neural networks to identify and qualitatively analyze the structural morphology of cells. Optimized the models to deal with class imbalance using class-sensitive training and sampling.

IIIT-Delhi, Dept. of Computer Science

June 2017 - Aug 2017

Summer Research Intern

Faculty Advisor: Dr. Saket Anand

Focus:

Lane detection on urban roads using semantic segmentation in autonomous vehicles.

UW-Madison Sept 2016 - Dec 2016

Visiting student

Faculty Advisor: Dr. Dane Morgan

Focus:

Used bayesian models and neural networks to predict changes in the mechanical properties of steel components due to alloy configurations.

MANUSCRIPTS

1. **Doshi, F.R.**, Konkle, T. (2022) Cortical topographic motifs emerge in a self-organized map of object space. *bioRxiv*, in press, doi:10.1101/2022.09.06.506403.

- 2. Conwell, C., **Doshi, F.**, Alvarez, G.A.. Human-Like Judgments of Stability Emerge from Purely Perceptual Features in Unsupervised and Supervised Models. (Paper in Prep)
- 3. Thirumalaraju, P., Bormann, CL., Kanakasabapathy, M., **Doshi, F.**, Souter, I., Dimitriadis, I., Shafiee, H.(2018). Automated sperm morpshology testing using artificial intelligence. In *Fertility and sterility.* 2018 Sep 1;110(4):e432.
- 4. Kanakasabapathy, M., Thirumalaraju, P., Kandula, H., **Doshi, F.**, Sivakumar, A., Kartik, D., Gupta, R., Pooniwala, R., Branda, J., Tsibris, A., Kuritzkes, D., Petrozza, J., Bormann, C., Shafiee H. (2021). Adaptive adversarial neural networks for the analysis of lossy and domain-shifted datasets of medical images. In *Nature Biomedical Engineering*, 2021.
- 5. Liu, Yc., Wu, H., Mayeshiba, T. et al. (2022). Machine learning predictions of irradiation embrittlement in reactor pressure vessel steels. In *npj Computational Materials*, 2022.

CONFERENCE TALKS

- 1. **Doshi, F.**, Konkle, T., Alvarez, G.A. (2022). Human-like signatures of contour integration in deep neural networks. Talk presented at *Vision Sciences Society*, 2022.
- 2. **Doshi, F.**, Konkle, T.(2021). Organizational motifs of cortical responses to objects emerge in topographic projections of deep neural networks. Talk presented at *Vision Sciences Society*, 2021.

CONFERENCE PAPERS

- 1. Conwell, C., **Doshi, F.**, Alvarez, G.A.(2019). Shared Representations of Stability in Humans, Supervised, & Unsupervised Neural Networks. In *Shared Visual Representations in Human and Machine Intelligence (SVRHM) workshop at NeurIPS 2019*.
- 2. Conwell, C., **Doshi, F.**, Alvarez, G.A.(2019). Human-Like Judgments of Stability Emerge from Purely Perceptual Features: Evidence from Supervised and Unsupervised Deep Neural Networks. In *Proceedings of the 3rd Conference on Cognitive Computational Neuroscience (CCN)*, 2019.
- 3. Chatterjee, S., Archana, V., Suresh, K., Saha, R., Gupta, R., **Doshi, F.(2017)**. Detection of non-technical losses using advanced metering infrastructure and deep recurrent neural networks. In *IEEE International Conference on Environment and Electrical Engineering*.

CONFERENCE POSTERS

- 1. **Doshi, F.** & Konkle (2022). Cortical topography motifs emerge from self-organization of a unified object space. In *Society for Neuroscience, San Diego, CA, November 12-16.*
- 2. **Doshi, F.**, Pailian, H., Alvarez, G.A.(2020). Using Deep Convolutional Neural Networks to Examine the Role of Representational Similarity in Visual Working Memory. In *Vision Science Society*, 2020.

INVITED TALKS

• Blitz Psychology Talk, Harvard University 2022

• International week, Pontificia Universidad Catolica del Peru (PUCP) 2022

• Program in Neuroscience, Harvard University 2023

HONORS AND AWARDS

 Fellowship for Students from India Awarded in honor of Prof. Amartya Sen

• Reimagine Education Award (Silver), Student-led Innovation for Next Tech Lab	2018
Quacquarelli Symonds (QS), Wharton School, University of Pennsylvania	
• Best Outgoing Student, Class of 2018 Department of Computer Science, SRM Institute of Science and Technology	2018
• National Champion Smart India Hackathon (India's biggest Hackathon)	2017

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Programming: Python (Pytorch, Tensorflow, Theano, Keras), Javascript, Matlab, C, C++, C#, Java **Experimental Techniques**: Computational Modelling, Behavioral Psychophysics

Statistics/Analysis: Non-parametric statistics, power analyses, simulation, resampling (bootstrapping), model comparison; factor analysis/principal component analysis, singular value decomposition

LEADERSHIP & ADVISING EXPERIENCE

Mind Brain Behavior Steering Committee

Next Tech Lab, Founding Member and Advisor

Co-founded a student-run research lab at SRM Institute of Science and Technology. Co-led over 160 students concentrating on Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Computational Biology, and Mixed Reality(AR/VR).

SELECT PERSONAL PROJECTS

- Feature-based categorical attention: Taking inspiration from work by Lindsay & Miller (2018), I isolated category-specific neurons in a pre-trained (on ImageNet) deep net (VGG-19). Category-wise normalized activation profiles were computed at the resolution of individual neurons and compared with the corresponding normalized gradient-based profiles/curves. Those neurons whose tuning and gradient profiles correlated significantly (hence had behavioral outcomes) were selected. Further analysis (t-tests) provided a stronger selection criterion. During the forward pass, these neurons are then modulated to improve categorization. An open question is to disentangle the attentional signals carried in feedforward, lateral, and top-down connections.
- Exploring the latent feature space of face representations in a reconstruction-based network using Deep Feature Consistency: Trained an adversarial variational autoencoder on the CelebA dataset. The KL divergence loss was replaced with an adversarial loss (Makhzani et al., 2016) and the pixel-wise loss was replaced with a deep feature consistent loss (Hou et al., 2016). Smooth interpolations in this latent space showed that the model was able to capture certain semantic aspects of different facial attributes.
- Neural Artistic Style Transfer for Videos: Produced results on a frame-by-frame basis and later improved it by initializing every new frame using optical flow from the previous frames.
- **Deep Sense:** A Restricted Boltzmann Machine (RBM) trained on a bunch of different songs by Hans Zimmer to produce novel monophonic music in his style.